CAUSES
	-Respiratory allergy: house dust mites, pollen and animal epithelia
	-Food allergy: more frequent in infants and children; cow milk, eggs, fish, soy or peanuts
	-Microbial agents: Staphylococcus aureus
	-Dry skin: long bathing, cold dry climate, insufficient use of emollients
	-Itching and subsequent scratching
	-Sweating: impermeable clothing, hot work places, stress
	-Chemical/physical irritants: smoking, clothes
	-Psychological stress

SYMPTOMS
	-increased susceptibility to allergic rhinitis and asthma
	-Lichenification: excessive itching which leads to thick, leathery patches of skin
	-Excoriation: repeated picking at one's own skin
	-Crusting
	-typically symmetric, chronic relapsing course
	-involving mainly the face, neck and the flexural surface of the elbow and knee

DIFFERENTIAL DIAGNOSIS
Atopic eczema may be distinguished from other types of dermatitis because of its typical course and associated stigmata.
	-Allergic Contact Dermatitis: lesions are usually pruritic and asymmetric. Eruptions are due to contact with specific allergen, and removal of offending agent results in resolution of symptoms.
	-Immunodeficiency: infants with a severe itch and generalized dermatitis in the setting of recurrent infections
	-Irritant Contact Dermatitis: common in diaper area, face, and extensor surfaces in children resulting from exposure to irritating substances. Typically less puritic.
	-Mycosis Fungoides: hypopigmented patches. Erythematous plaques in random distribution. Patients tend to be older, with an average age of 50 years.
	-Psoriasis: well-circumscribed, erythematous lesions with silver scale that show a predilection for elbows and knees.
	-Scabies: severe pruritus, particularly at night. Burrows may be evident. The wrists, ankles, palms, soles, interdigital spaces, armpit, waist, and groin are the most commonly affected sites.
	-Tinea Corporis: manifests as a single lesion

PREVENTIVE TREATMENT
	-Moisturisers: used every day to stop the skin from becoming dry
	-Try to reduce scratching whenever possible. Keep nails short and clean to minimize damage to the skin from unintentional scratching.
	-Avoid triggers that can cause eczema flare-ups. This can be certain foods, fabrics, soaps, etc.

WHEN TO SEE A DOCTOR
	-When a bacterial infection occurs
		*fluid oozing from the skin
		*a yellow crust on the surface
		*small yellowish-white spots in the eczema
		*swollen and sore
		*high temperature (fever)
	-It is possible for the eczema to be infected with the herpes simplex virus, which can develop into eczema herpeticum
		*areas of painful eczema that quickly get worse
		*fluid-filled blisters that break open and leave small, shallow open sores
		*a high temperature
